Welcome to this introduction to the blockchain.
First, we're going to answer the question What is the blockchain?
I blockchain is a ledger that is shared and immutable.
Firstly, what's a ledger?
Well, Ledger is a place where transactions are recorded, transactions like you sending money to your
friend or a company selling a product and receiving some money in return.
Now, let's focus on shared and immutable.
A blockchain is shared because everyone can view the ledger and everyone can see the same copy of the
ledger.
This is different from, say, a banks ledger in a banks ledger.
The bank can see all the transactions, but you can only see your transactions.
But in a blockchain, you can see all the transactions.
The blockchain is also immutable, immutable means it can't be changed.
And what that means is once a transaction is recorded on the blockchain, it's permanent.
You can't remove the transaction or change the transaction.
Let's look into more detail about how a blockchain works AI blockchain is literally a chain of blocks.
Each block contains a list of transactions.
As each transaction occurs, it's recorded into a block.
Multiple transactions are added to the block.
Then the block is added to the end of the existing blockchain in a process called mining.
And what's special about mining is that it means that once a transaction is stored on the blockchain,
it cannot be changed.
The exact mechanism, why is not something I'm going to cover in this video, because that would require
a long winded discussion on cryptography hashes the nonsense which isn't necessary for you to start
programming for Solana.
But it's worth mentioning that mining is the reason why the blockchain is immutable.
What are the benefits of the blockchain?
There are three decentralization of trust, immutability and security.
Decentralization of trust, this is so special and unique to the blockchain, the way finance works
now, we delegate the trust of our money over to a third party.
I bet that right now you have some money stored in a bank because you trust the bank to give you your
money when you need it.
With the blockchain, though, you don't need to trust a third party like a bank to control your money.
You can trust the blockchain itself.
And what that means is that you don't have to worry about the bank taking a long time to give you your
money and you don't have to worry about bank fees.
Immutability is another benefit once a transaction is added onto the blockchain.
It is impossible for that transaction to be changed.
This is important because it prevents fraud and manipulation and provides us with increased transparency.
You don't have to worry about your bank being corrupt.
And security.
It's much, much, much more difficult to hack into the blockchain than into a bank.
Blockchain uses cryptography and algorithms of consensus to have a practically unbreakable security.
To be able to also record it would be necessary to control or deceive at least 51 percent of the network,
which in terms of hardware and electricity costs, make this practically impossible.
I mentioned banks a fair amount in this video.
A lot of people are investing in the blockchain because they believe that the blockchain will eventually
replace banks.
It's quite a long term goal.
Banks still operate today, but that's why you're so lucky because you're watching this video and following
this course, now you are early by learning about the blockchain and how to develop for the blockchain.
Now you all leagues ahead of the rest in a technology that will change the world.